<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Yingxin Lin</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Yingxin Lin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>scClassify</title>
      <link>/project/scclassify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/scclassify/</guid>
      <description>Cell type identification is a key computational challenge in single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) data. To capitalize on the large collections of well-annotated scRNAseq datasets, we present scClassify, a hierarchical classification framework based on ensemble learning. scClassify can identify cells from published scRNAseq datasets more accurately and more finely than in the original publications. We also estimate the cell number needed for accurate classification anywhere in a cell type hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scDC</title>
      <link>/project/scdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/scdc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scMerge</title>
      <link>/project/scmerge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/scmerge/</guid>
      <description>Concerted examination of multiple collections of single cell RNA-Seq (scRNA-Seq) data promises further biological insights that cannot be uncovered with individual datasets. However, such integrative analyses are challenging and require sophisticated methodologies. To enable effective interrogation of multiple scRNA-Seq datasets, we have developed a novel algorithm, named scMerge, that removes unwanted variation by combining stably expressed genes and utilizing pseudo-replicates across datasets. Analysis of large collections of publicly available datasets demonstrates that scMerge performs well in multiple scenarios and enhances biological discovery, including inferring cell developmental trajectories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>