<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data integration | Yingxin Lin</title>
    <link>/tag/data-integration/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/data-integration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data integration</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hubac6f24c8653994461d9d2f1603b1cf3_3281_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Data integration</title>
      <link>/tag/data-integration/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>scJoint: transfer learning for data integration of atlas-scale single-cell RNA-seq and ATAC-seq</title>
      <link>/publication/scjoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/scjoint/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CiteFuse enables multi-modal analysis of CITE-seq data</title>
      <link>/publication/citefuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/citefuse/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-modality data integration</title>
      <link>/project/citefuse-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/citefuse-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Multi-modal profiling of single cells represents one of the latest technological advancements in molecular biology. Among various single-cell multi-modal strategies, cellular indexing of transcriptomes and epitopes by sequencing (CITE-seq) allows simultaneous quantification of two distinct species: RNA and cell-surface proteins. Here, we introduce CiteFuse, a streamlined package consisting of a suite of tools for doublet detection, modality integration, clustering, differential RNA and protein expression analysis, antibody-derived tag evaluation, ligand–receptor interaction analysis and interactive web-based visualization of CITE-seq data. We demonstrate the capacity of CiteFuse to integrate the two data modalities and its relative advantage against data generated from single-modality profiling using both simulations and real-world CITE-seq data. Furthermore, we illustrate a novel doublet detection method based on a combined index of cell hashing and transcriptome data. Finally, we demonstrate CiteFuse for predicting ligand–receptor interactions by using multi-modal CITE-seq data. Collectively, we demonstrate the utility and effectiveness of CiteFuse for the integrative analysis of transcriptome and epitope profiles from CITE-seq data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single modality data integration</title>
      <link>/project/scmerge-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/scmerge-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) profiling has exploded in recent years and enabled new biological knowledge to be discovered at the single-cell level. Successful and flexible integration of scRNA-Seq datasets from multiple sources promises to be an effective avenue to obtain further biological insights. This study presents a comprehensive approach to integration for scRNA-seq data analysis. It addresses the challenges involved in successful integration of scRNA-seq datasets by using the knowledge of genes that appear not to change across all samples and a robust algorithm to infer pseudoreplicates between datasets. This information is then consolidated into a single-factor model that enables tailored incorporation of prior knowledge. The effectiveness of scMerge is demonstrated by extensive comparison with other approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scMerge leverages factor analysis, stable expression, and pseudoreplication to merge multiple single-cell RNA-seq datasets</title>
      <link>/publication/scmerge/scmerge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/scmerge/scmerge/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
